airforce.com 2015-06-09

# Privacy Policy - airforce.com

## Privacy and Security Notice

Effective date: January 28, 2013

The United States Air Force Recruiting Services websites, including but not limited to AIRFORCE.COM, AFROTC.com and ACADEMYADMISSIONS.COM, are provided as a public service by the United States Air Force Recruiting Service and the Department of the Air Force. This Privacy Policy applies to the United States Air Force Recruiting Service website, airforce.com, and describes the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information on this website. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE OR SUBMIT ANY INFORMATION TO THIS WEBSITE.

Please note that the Department of the Air Force website is governed by its own separate security and privacy policy. To view the Department of the Air Force security and privacy policy, click [here](http://www.af.mil/Disclaimer.aspx). You may also be able to access third-party social networks, such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and Google+ from airforce.com. When doing so, please understand that these social networks have their own set of information practices. We strongly recommend that you read that social network’s privacy policy and terms and conditions to understand how it collects, uses and shares information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third-party websites.

### Collection and Use

On this website, you can contact us to learn more about how to apply for the U.S. Air Force or to ask a general question or provide a general comment. When contacting us, we may collect personal information about you, such as your name, email address, phone number and mailing address so that we can contact you or respond to your request. 

Certain features of this website may require you to submit additional personal information or register in order to be able to use those features. For example, if you wish to use the Live Chat feature or play a game on our site, you may need to register by submitting your name, gender, date of birth, email address, mailing address and phone number. This information will be used to register you so that you can use those features of this site. We may also use this information to provide you with materials you may find interesting about the U.S. Air Force. It is our policy not to contact you unless you have requested to be contacted. We may ask additional information about your background, such as whether you have been convicted of a felony, whether you are a single parent, whether you have ever used illegal drugs or whether you are a conscientious objector. This information may be used for preliminary screening eligibility purposes. You may choose instead to create an account and log in to our site using a third-party social network, such as Facebook. For more information on creating an account and logging in using a third-party social network, see the “Third-Party Social Networks” section below.

We may also collect nonpersonal information for the purposes of operating and improving our website. For example, we collect technical and usage information, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, date and time you accessed our website, browser type and referring URL. This information will be used to create summary statistics, which are used for such purposes as assessing what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications and identifying system performance or problem areas. 

This site may use cookies and other web technologies to enable certain features and protect unauthorized users (such as children under the age of 13) from accessing certain features of our site. We may also use clear GIFs (i.e., pixel tags) provided by our third-party advertisers to help manage and tailor our online advertising efforts appropriate to your interests. This allows us, among other functions, to learn which ads bring users to our website. The information we collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable (it does not include your name, address, telephone number or email address). If you would like to opt out of having your information used for this purpose, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Raw data logs are used for no other purposes. Our policy is to destroy these data logs in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration General Schedule 20.

### Sharing

Our policy is to limit the sharing of your information with third parties in the following circumstances:  

  1. Third-Party Service Providers. We may use third-party service providers, such as Atlas Analytics or database administrators, to help provide or improve the certain aspects of this website. We may share your information with these third-party service providers so that they may provide their services to us. 
  2. Third-Party Advertisers. We may use third-party advertisers to deliver advertising to you. We may share your information with these third-party advertisers for the purposes of delivering these advertisements. 
  3. Legal Purposes. We may provide your information to third parties as required by law or to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement authority. 
  4. Health or Safety. We may share your information when we have a good faith belief that there is an emergency that poses a threat to the health or safety of you, another person or the public generally. 

### Third-Party Social Networks

You may be able to access third-party social networks, such as Facebook, Twitter and Google+, from our website. For example, when you Like one of our posts, that post may appear on your Facebook page. Please note that these websites have their own set of information practices and privacy policies and the Air Force Recruiting Service is not responsible for the information you choose to submit in these forums.

You may also choose to create an account and log in to our site through a third-party social network. For example, you can create an account and log in using your Facebook account information through Facebook Connect. When you log in to our site with your social network account information, you are permitting the United States Air Force Recruiting Service to access certain social network account information about you so that we can deliver our online content to you. 

### Children

This website is not directed to children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children. If you are under the age of 13, please stop using this website. It is our policy not to knowingly solicit or permit children under the age of 13 to provide their personal information for any purpose. In the event that we learn that we have inadvertently collected personal information from children under the age of 13, we will take reasonable measures to promptly delete the information. 

### Security

For security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this government computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

### Changes to this Policy

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you check this website from time to time as we may revise this Privacy Policy. We will provide you with notice of a material change to the Privacy Policy by either email or by posting it on our website. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information. By continuing to use this website after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

### 10 U.S.C. 503 Enlistment/Accessions

Recruiting campaigns, Air Education and Training Command Instruction 36-2002, Recruiting Procedures for the Air Force, and 10 U.S.C. 8013, Secretary of the Air Force; powers and duties delegation by. PURPOSE: To obtain necessary information to respond to your request for information about a career in the Air Force. ROUTINE USE: No disclosure of this information will be made outside of the Department of Defense. DISCLOSURE: Voluntary: However, if the information is not provided, we will be unable to contact you and notify you of the possible Air Force opportunities available to you.

### Questions

If you have any questions or comments about the information presented in this policy, please contact us [here](mailto:webmaster@airforce.com).
